<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Greg Barbieri</title><link>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Greg Barbieri</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gfbarbieri.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Birthday Problem</title><link>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/probability/birthday_problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/probability/birthday_problem/</guid><description>If there are n people in the room, the probability that all n birthdays are distinct equals (none are equal):
$\displaystyle\prod_{k=1}^{n}{\frac{365-(k-1)}{365}}$
Therefore, the probability is 1 minus the results of the product.
Imports import numpy as np import matplotlib.pyplot as plt Calculate Probability indiv_prob_list = [] for num in range(1,101): indiv_prob = (365-(num-1))/365 indiv_prob_list.append(indiv_prob) Plot Probability plt.plot(np.linspace(1,100,100), 1-np.cumprod(indiv_prob_list))</description></item><item><title>Counting Poker Hands</title><link>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/counting/counting_poker_hands/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/counting/counting_poker_hands/</guid><description>This problem is taken directly from Professor Morin&amp;rsquo;s Probability For the Enthusiastic Beginner, Chapter 1, page 38.
In a standard 52-card deck, how many different five-card poker hands are there of each of the following types?
Full House Straight Flush Flush Straight One pair Two pairs Three of a kind Four of a kind None of the above For each type, it is understood that we don&amp;rsquo;t count hands that also fall into a higher category.</description></item><item><title>Removing Repetitions</title><link>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/counting/count_remove_repetitions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/counting/count_remove_repetitions/</guid><description>This question comes from Professor David Morin&amp;rsquo;s book, Probability For the Enthusiastic Beginner, Chapter 1, page 26.
We know that the number of ordered sets of three people chosen from five people is $5 \times 4 \times 3 = 60$. Reproduce this results by starting with the naive answer of $5^3 = 125$ ordered sets where repetitions are allowed, and then subtracting off the number of triplets that have repeated people.</description></item><item><title>Roll a Die, Flip a Coin</title><link>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/counting/counting_coin_die/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/counting/counting_coin_die/</guid><description>This question comes from Professor David Morin&amp;rsquo;s book, Probability For the Enthusiastic Beginner, Chapter 1, page 26.
One person rolls two six-sided dice, and another person flips six two-sided coins. Which setup has the larger number of possible outcomes, assuming that the order matters? There are two situations presented in the problem:
One person rolls two six-sided dice. One person flips six two-sided coins. An identical way to phrase the first situation is, one person rolls one six-sided die twice.</description></item><item><title>Counting, an Introduction</title><link>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/counting/counting_introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_tutorials/fun/counting/counting_introduction/</guid><description>This introductory question comes directly from Probability For the Enthusiastic Beginner, Chapter 1, page 26.
Six girls and four boys are to be assigned to ten seats in a row, with the stipulations that a girl sits in the third seat and a boy sits in the eighth seat. How many arrangements are possible? If we ignore the stipulations for a moment, then the question becomes “how many arrangements of 10 people (6 girls + 4 boys) are possible?</description></item><item><title>Code Tutorial Topics</title><link>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_topics/code_topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gfbarbieri.github.io/code_topics/code_topics/</guid><description>Machine Learning Basics -- Python Data Analysis -- Fun Exercises Probability Birthday Problem Counting Counting Poker Hands Removing Repetitions Roll a Die, Flip a Coin Counting, an Introduction</description></item></channel></rss>